# KEENAN BRANT

Barnsley, South Yorkshire 07867861565 | keenan.brant@yahoo.co.uk

Portfolio: https://kbrant.dev

GitHub: https://github.com/The-Nightman

## **PROFILE**

A junior software developer with full stack programming skills with prior technical knowledge of computer hardware and software looking for a role where I can utilise my skills and expand upon them with new knowledge learned on the job. I initially spent 2 years at Sheffield Hallam University studying Cyber Security and Computer Networks, in the May of 2023 I joined the Northcoders Software Development Bootcamp. I have been learning fundamental coding skills and practices with a focus on JavaScript and JS frameworks and libraries.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Software development languages and practices including JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, React and React Native, Test Driven Development using Jest, Agile methods, HTML, CSS and TailwindCSS. GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/The-Nightman">https://github.com/The-Nightman</a>
- Well versed in IT technical skills including maintaining and installing computer hardware directly and the installation of software.
- Proficient in utilizing software packages including MS Office suite, Windows troubleshooting software and Adobe Creative cloud Suite

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Junior Developer, Northcoders Software Dev Bootcamp**

15th May 2023 to 11th Aug 2023

- Award winning software development bootcamp teaching Full-Stack coding skills with a focus on Web development using the PERN stack and demonstrated through solo and pair programming project-based learning portfolio pieces.
- Back-end skills demonstrated by building and hosting a RESTful news API made with NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL and the Jest test suite. This API was built and documented with multiple GET, PATCH, POST and DELETE routes and custom error handling using express middleware.
- Front-end skills demonstrated by a responsive mobile-first news web-app built using HTML, CSS, React, JavaScript and MUI libraries, this is a dynamic web-app linking to a RESTful back-end API that can be interacted with and changed through user actions such as ratings and comments.

#### **Library Front Desk, Wath Public Library (Work Placement)**

Dec 2017 to Dec 2017

A Public library located in the town centre of Wath that provides basic library services to the local area as well as spaces for community groups

- Working with the library database system to manage outbound and incoming inventory and reservations
- Stock keeping and physical organisation of stock via library database system
- Providing basic customer service in the form of direction and IT technical support
- · management of incoming calls and payment to front desk or escalating to library manager

## **Product line worker, Vortex Clothing Co Ltd (Work Placement)**

Dec 2015 to Dec 2015

A small clothing printing and embroidery company that provides to-specification embroidery or printing of graphics on clothing for customers ranging from schools and university societies to large construction firms.

- · Operation of graphics application machinery
- End of line quality assurance checks for products to meet the required standards
- Preparation of graphics transferred from digital to physical format for machinery
- · Stocking and maintenance of bespoke graphics equipment for regular customers and large orders
- Managing logistics and paperwork of orders due for distribution

# **EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS**

•	Sheffield Hallam University –	Cyber Security and Computer Networks	2018 – 2020
---	-------------------------------	--------------------------------------	-------------

Dearne Valley College, Manvers - BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma ICT (DMM)

Netherwood ALC, Wombwell - 6 GCSE's and 1 BTEC including English, Maths and
Science at grades C

## **HOBBIES / INTERESTES**

- Maintenance of personal PC system including keeping in good functioning order or upgrading as required.
- Fishing allowing me to use problem solving skills in a dynamic environment.
- Personal physical fitness involving technical knowledge and record keeping.

#### REFERENCES

Available on request